Guide to the Lillian Herlands Hornstein Papers 1930-1980 MC.140
New York University Archives
- Series IV: Miscellaneous Research Material
  - Tacitus, Tasso, Thucydides, Tragedy: clippings and notes., undated (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Tolstoy, Turgenev, Tolkien, Toynbee and Trollope., undated (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Sir Gowain and the Earl of Carlisle, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058140 0
  - Bologna and Gowain, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Gemerides, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Guy of Warwick, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Havelok, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Huon of Bordeaux, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Ipomadon, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Isumbras, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Kay, undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - King of Tars. Including Hornstein's published article and bibliography, undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Knight of Curtesy, undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Lancelot of the Laik (du lac), undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Sir Launfal, undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Libeaus Desconus, undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Little Arthur of Brittany, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Melusine, undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Merlin, undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Nennius, undated (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Octovian, undated (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Olive, undated (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Prester, John, undated (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Partonope of Blois, undated (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Perceval, the holy Grail, undated (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Teseida, by Giovanni Boccaccio, translated into English by Bernadette, undated (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - The Theseid of the nuptials of Emilia, and Boccacio's Ameto's translations, undated (Box 21, Folder 24.b)
  - Bibliographical index A-B, undated (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - C-D, undated (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - E-F, undated (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - G-H, undated (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - I-J, undated (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - K-L, undated (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - M-N, undated (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - O-P, undated (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Q-R, undated (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - S-T, undated (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - U-V-W-X-Y-Z, undated (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - The Bodleian Picture Books: English Illumination 13-14 Centuries and, undated (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Country life. from the Book of Rural Occupations by Petrus Crescentius, 1470, undated (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Pictures of Scribes and Teachers, undated (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Life and the Arts, by Willis Wager, Three main installments, undated (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Caxton, William. The Boke of Eneydos. Papers, notes, clippings, undated (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - English handwriting, terminal contractions, examples of english, undated (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Female Longevity and diet in the middle ages by Vern Bullough and Cameron, undated (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Illustration of the book of abridgments, pictures, description and negative, undated (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - Lyrics, Carols, Ballads, including Chaucer, undated (Box 21, Folder 44)
  - Joseph Bedier. A study of Tristan et Iseult, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058141 8
  - Black Literature, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Boccaccio, related to Chaucer. Includes index card collection and clippings, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Chess, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - China. Liberty Magazine, of religious freedom, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - College English, correspondence with publication, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Comments on lawyers writings, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Committees. includes a report on PhD requirements, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Composition. Final exams formats, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Dante, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Drama, misc. syllabus and papers, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Danielsson correspondence, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Dylan Thomas and Thomas a Beckett, undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - English Graduate Association of NYU, Summaries from 1950-60 for Newsletters., undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - EGA Newsletter, undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Erasmus in English, a newsletter published by University of Toronto, undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Euripides, notes, papers, clippings, undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Fielding, undated (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - FILLM congress, also articles on Fawkes and Myrick Land, undated (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Gaylord, Alan, correspondence, undated (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - German. Related to the German-English languages studies., undated (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Gide, Andre, undated (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - John Gower, bibliographies and notes, clippings and articles, undated (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Goya, article, undated (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Greene, Richard. Correspondence, undated (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Halliwell-Phillips correspondence, undated (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Hook, Sidney, undated (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Hopkins, Gerard Manley, undated (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Italian language exam and article about Italy, undated (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Ireland and Ireland Today, Bulletin of the Department of Foreign Affairs, undated (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Jung, Carl Gustav. Clippings, undated (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Joyce, James. Papers, undated (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Kafka, Franz, undated (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Kerouac, Jack. Clippings, undated (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Modern Literature. Clippings, bibliography and papers on contemporary, undated (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - January, The Duc de Berry at Table, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058142 6
  - February, The Village Under the Snow, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - March, The Chateau de Lusignan, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - April, The Chateau de Dourdan, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - May, The Town of Riom, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - June, The Palace and Sainte-Chapelle, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - July, The Chateau de Poitiers, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - August, The Chateau d'Etampes, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - September, The Chateau de Saumur, undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - October, The Louvre, undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - November, Gathering the Acorns, undated (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - December, The Chateau de Vincennes, undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Verve "Les Tres Riches Heures du Duc de Berry" Fifteenth Century Calendarr. Text by Henri Malo, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058143 4
  - Islendingabok, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified Print and Picture, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Facsimile Editions by Urs Graf-Verlag, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Canterbury Tales (Black and white prints), undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Arthurian Legends (Black and white prints), undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified Manuscript, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - King Robert of Sicilly MSS Photostats, undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Fairfax MS, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - 2300 Years of Medical Costume, undated (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Schools of Illumination Prints (1914), undated (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - English Court Hand 1066 to 1500 Part II: Plates; "The Ellesmere Chaucer: Knight's Tale of MS. ca. 1400; Tale of Melibeus. MS. ca 1400; Monk's tale. MS ca. 1400; "Histories of Troy" Caxton. 1475. ***French Posters being stretched, La Varende. Histoire de la Marine en Maquettes (Aout 3-31, 1966), undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058144 2
  - Du Debarquement en Agleterre de Guillaume Le Conquerant, undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Tapisserie de la Reine Mathilde (1066-1966) IX Centenaire de la bataille de Hastings/France Normandie Bayeux, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Series V: Personal Papers and Articles
  Hornstein's papers from Graduate school, notebooks, speeches, Curriculum Vitae, publishedarticles and editions, and correspondence. (Box 26)
  - Hornstein's personal papers from grad school, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058145 9
  - Hornstein's College notebooks I, Middle English Romances, Modern English, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Hornstein's College notebooks II, Bible, Middle English 13-14C., undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Allegory, Philology, Epic, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Speeches, miscellaneous, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Speeches at MLA, undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Hornstein's curriculum vitae, complete list of her publications, undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Studies on King Robert of Sicily. Hornstein's article, published at PMLA, March, 1964. Plus reprints of study, undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - King Robert of Sicily article related correspondence, undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Petrarch's Laelius, Chaucer Lollius? Hornstein's article published at PMLA, undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - American Speech. Review by Hornstein: "Folk Tales of England and North America and, article on Park Patter from Dec. 1940 issue, undated (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - The Wyf of Bathe and the merchant: From sex to 'secte'. Hornstein article published at the Chaucer Review, Vol. 3, No. 1, undated (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - David C. Fowler, A Literacy History of the Popular Ballad. Reviewed by Hornstein. Published in the English Language Notes. Vol VII, No. 1., undated (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Modern Language Review. April 1952: Miscellaneous notes. October 1957: "'Marie Toy...Maie Poinct': An Anglo-latin Parallel." July 1964: review of Annotated Bibliography of Edmund Spenser, 1937-1960. October 1941: "New Analogues to the King of Tarss.", undated (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Janua Linguarum. "Reduplicatives Redivivus: from ACK-ACK through GO-GO to ZIG ZAG and a little beyond." by Ms. Hornstein and issues of Middle English texts, Ms. Hornstein was editor., undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Publications: "A Folklore Theme in the King of Tars." The Philosophical Quaterly, XX, 1 (January 1941) "The Historical Background of the King of Tars," Speculum, Vol. XVI, October 1941, No. 4; "Trivet's Constance and the King of Tars, MLN May 1940; "Analisis of Imagery, PMLA Sept. 1942; "'Though this Be Madness': Insanity in the Theater" College English, Oct 1945 "Some Chaucer Allusions by Sir Edward Coke" Modern Language Notes, November 1945; "Imagery and Biography: They are of the Imagination all Compact: College English 1947; "Rugby Chapel and Exodus," Modern Language Review, April 1952, undated (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - USA Today article about the Hornsteins, undated (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Female Serpent, undated (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Personal Correspondence, mainly from nephews, undated (Box 26, Folder 19)